I love how Max starts out his day.
I'll show you.
Okay, check, check, there we go. Good afternoon everybody. Thank you so much for coming out. The seventh annual Medford Jazz Festival. The fourth year it's been on the back patio. It just keeps getting better every single time. So it's great to see some folks that have been here in past years and some that haven't.
Welcome to the West Medford Community Center. I know Terry Carter is going to tell you more about that, but in the meantime, my name is Jonathan Fagan. I've been leading this for, well, ever since 2020, which obviously was a very different year for live music, but this has been such a joy to bring all of these local artists here.
Before we get started, I'll leave it to Terry to introduce the group, but just need to thank our sponsors, because none of this would be possible without them. So thank you to Medford Arts Council, to the, yes, we can clap for every single one of them if we want to. The Arts Alive Foundation, yeah, headed by the great May Markabrook, who is just an amazing cultural ambassador for the city. For Berkeley's Institute of Global Jazz, you'll hear from them tomorrow.
uh... and also berkeley's institute for jazz and gender justice late led by a great terry lynn kerrington who grew up right around here to have been i was enjoy telling people about that we don't know to local music schools also in winchester community music school
Right down the street, pretty much, Morningside Music Studio. Heard a couple of their students last night with the Vertigo Trio. And also to all of our Patreon subscribers. You know, we all have too many monthly subscriptions. Well, Patreon is a good one. I promise.
That's just a few dollars a month. It's a normal subscription service, but it helps us sustain jam sessions and also fund all of the artists that are performing at our festival. To a couple of other individual donors, including Susan Klein, Steve Shulman, and Bob Bean, they've really pushed us over the edge. Yes. And then I'm trying to make sure that I don't, oh yeah, and of course the services of Audience Sound Company, which Avi Fagan over there.
To Medford Community Media with Jim over there manning some, and Bruce also over there on the camera. Let me not forget about him. He's also on our board. And lastly, and most importantly, the West Medford Community Center for supporting us here. We have a food vendor inside in the Danish Pastry House. So if you haven't gotten anything already, they're really good.
So maybe during a break between the sets, I'm sure you won't want to miss any of this. And last to a board of directors, that's been a real joy just to get some help in all the facets of planning this. Shayla McDermott, who's right there in action passing out programs to people.
uh... to bruce and i mentioned over there in the cameras recently live or up men in the t-shirt station uh... and to our yet to our two volunteers i love how intergenerational this is uh... we've got to kota over there helping out um... go well who's over there helping out with sound and yet because uh... and roman see there are too many i can even keep track of them all yeah
So with that, I'm going to turn it over to Terry Carter. He's going to tell you a little bit about the community center and introduce this first group.
So I like to say that Jonathan and I kind of met at what we refer to as the intersection of jazz and social justice. And you'll hear a little bit more about that tomorrow when we play the last set of the third day of the Jazz Festival. We had a wonderful evening. It was just...
spectacular music, a great crowd. So we're really, really excited about what we have to present to you today. Just a quick word about the West Medford Community Center. We've been here for over 90 years. This is the second building on this site. And the West Medford community has been the traditional heart of the African-American presence in West Medford, in Medford proper.
And Duggar Park was named after Lieutenant Colonel Edward Duggar, who was one of our local heroes. But this building, 111 Arlington Street, really, really represents the home for
West Medford's black community when it really, really was without a home. When the community first started, there were really only three streets that people of color could live on. It was Arlington Street, which is right behind us, there was Lincoln Street, the street over from that, and then there was Jerome Street.
We were redlined out of everywhere else in Medford. So that's where this community began. And in the 30s, the men got together and decided that they wanted to have something they could call their own, where they could gather and socialize and so forth. But by 1945, they realized that this whole notion of men alone wasn't going to work.
And the womanly influence took over. So around 1945, those men got together. They went and got a building, a Quonset hut or old military barracks from Boston. They carted it here on one of the men's moving trucks. And they poured a foundation and built the old community center on this site. And as I say, this is the second building on the site.
But again, it represents over 90 years of African-American history in the city of Medford. And if you go inside, and hopefully you will, if nothing else but to gather some food from Danish Pastry Hut, you'll notice two levels of history.
The top level is the West Medford Elder Project. The level below that is the West Medford Afro-American Remembrance Project. And it tells really, really the lion's share of the history of this community. So hopefully, you'll go inside and avail yourself of some of that history. All right, now to the matter at hand. So I have known Farahi Malik for
Is it seven, eight years now? It's probably that. Yeah, and our story began as Farai being one of the singers at one of our mutual friends Stacey Clayton's annual gospel concerts over at Somerville Community Baptist Church.
And Stacey had a way of, and I don't know how she did it, but she had a way of getting aspiring superstars to come sing in her choir, right? There have been several of them, and Farai is one of them. And not only aspiring superstar singers, but also musicians. And some of the musicians back here are musicians that came out of that tradition as well. So it's Farai Malik on vocals and acoustic guitar.
It's Grayson Hillen on vocals and electric bass. It's Jacob Means on vocals and the mandolin. So you're in for a treat there. My man, Max Ridley on the big sexy, the big upright bass. And Hector Falu Guzman on the drum set, okay.
Grayson? OK. All right. So I think I got everybody. So now what I do is I get out of the way, and I let the professional musicians take over. Ladies and gentlemen, the Farahi Malik Quintet. How's everybody doing? We doing all right?
Thank you so much, Terry, for having us. We're so glad to be here. And we're excited to be playing this set of music for you today. So we're going to do some music, a couple tunes off my first EP, Edge of the Earth, that came out last year, and then some new singles that I have out, and some music that we're about to record tomorrow in Nashville with this guy. Oh my goodness. So we both have very early morning flights.
But we're really excited to play this new music for you, because not very many audiences have heard it. So if you like the new music, tell us yes. And if you don't, don't tell us. This first one is called Every Heartbeat. It's my latest, or second to last single. This came out last November.
I came through a valley cold one winter night and shining on a hill a yellow beam of light gazing in my wonder
Through the frosted trees It felt so real I questioned if it was a dream Walking under moonlight
Feelings absent from my heart for years Now every color is brighter, all I smell is sweet I feel the gentle snow fall softly on my cheek Something I was missing finally complete I'm seeing with brand new eyes and I feel you in every heartbeat
Standing now beside you, falling into your embrace, I'm understood and love completely for all day. From my shining hour to my darkest night,
But something I was missing, finally a complete break I'm singing with brand new eyes and
I feel you in every heartbeat I came through a valley cold on winter night and shining on a hill a yellow beam of light
Thank you so much. This next one is called In Her Closet, and it's off my EP, Edge of the Earth. And this is about how
We all have these little parts of ourselves that we don't necessarily want the world to see. It might be a problem that we're dealing with, a struggle, maybe something in our past, something in our present, but as we grow into ourselves and we grow to love who we are, it becomes harder and harder to hide those parts because we just want to be seen and loved for exactly who we are. This one's called In Her Closet.
In her closet she has dreams, shiny shoes and magazines Empty bottles of natural wine, and this is why she lies In her closet she has faith, mustard seed, unplanted state Skeletons and bullet rye, and this is why she cries
she cries oh she longs to live an honest life and as she grows it gets harder to hide the things in her closet holding back her life in her closet she has pain silk scarves and a silver chain sandals telling her to leave this is why she grieves
She has fear, cigarettes and madam's beer, hoodies from forgotten times. This is why she cries. And oh, she lies. Oh, she cries. Oh, she longs to live an honest life. As she grows, it gets harder to hide the things in her closet holding
In her closet she has joy, formal gowns, her favorite toys, running shoes, grandma's meal coat, this is what she knows. But in her closet she has stress, at a band and suits to press, dirty laundry on the floor, she knows she's worth more.
Thank you so much.
So this summer I've been playing at all different kinds of festivals. Bluegrass festivals, Americana festivals, some jazz festivals. And usually a lot of times the audience will say, do we have any jazz fans in the house? But I know we do here, right? So this next one, one of the things I love to do in my writing is write songs based off of standards that I love.
And so this one I wrote based off of a standard that I love called Everything Happens to Me. Are we familiar with that? Some folks familiar with it? So it goes like, I make a date for golf and you can bet your life it rains. I try to give a party and the guy upstairs complains. I guess I'll go through life just catching colds and missing trains.
Everything happens to me. So it's very woe is me, and then the bridge is like, oh, I lost my lady love, and she doesn't love me anymore, and woe is me, and everything's terrible. So I went through something last year that made me feel like writing a woe is me song and was very inspired by that. This is called Today is Not My Day. We're just tuning up here.
Our instruments got used to the hot weather. Yes. All of our instruments are very angry right now. OK. We good? Is that OK?
That's better. All right. It's called, Today Is Not My Day. Woke up to gray skies that covered the blue. Reached for the place where I used to find you. Walked out the door with a thorn in my shoe. Today is not my day.
♪ Got to the car and my tire was flat ♪ ♪ Wonder what you would have done about that ♪ ♪ Hit every red light on the buses I sat ♪ ♪ Today is not my day ♪ ♪ Time surely heals all wounds ♪
But tomorrow can't come too soon Got home from work, left my keys in the door The candle burned out and it dripped on the floor I'm all out of wine, I can't cry anymore Today is not my day
Bye!
do do
Time surely heals all wounds, but tomorrow
I'll close my eyes and you're here next to me. Everything's just as we hoped it would be. Then the sun rises to shatter my dreams. Today is not my day. Today is not my day. Today is not my day.
Jacob Means, mandolin. Max Ridley on bass. We got Grayson Hill on guitar. Hector Falu Guzman on drums. I said that right. It's such a pleasure to play with these guys. I've been playing with Jacob for, shoot,
15 years? Has it been that long? We went to school together at New England Conservatory many moons ago. And I've been playing with Max here for, I don't know, a long time too. But it's just really special to share the stage with these guys. Next, when we got here,
I've been doing a lot of co-writing in Nashville recently, and one of the wonderful women I write with, her name is Melody Walker, and I'm from Idaho originally, and she said, we should write a song about Idaho. I'm like, I don't want to write a song about Idaho. She's like, no, come on, come on, it'll be fun. And so I wrote this about how while I love Boston,
Sometimes I fantasize about leaving the cold and the traffic and all the wonderful things that make Boston, Boston and moving back home to the Rocky Mountains. So this one's called Going Home to the Rockies. I do love Boston, please don't be mad at me. One, two, three.
Sittin' tired of these silly lies Those big buildings don't treat me right My subway car is always breakin' down Lot of fake homes on Acorn Street And those cobblestones, they hurt my feet I'll go crazy if I don't get my ticket out
City light only broke my heart I heard she's a-walkin' So I'm packin' up and skippin' town
♪ A little more quiet, a little more peace ♪ ♪ A little more warmth can be evergreen ♪ ♪ So I'm headed west with a fiddle on my back ♪ ♪ Grilling up steaks from the neighbor's ranch close ♪ ♪ Fenway Franks wouldn't stand a chance ♪ ♪ So I'll shoot you to boogie ♪ ♪ This time I'm not coming back ♪
I'm
Thanks so much. This next one we got for you is... I'm gonna just retune here for you guys. This is my latest single, it came out last week.
and uh thank you it's in collaboration with the steel drivers wonderful bluegrass group um it's called prayer for the people
So much trouble in the land, oh Lord, oh Lord Heal this broken land, broken land, broken land
broken man, broken man so many living in despair, oh no
So many angry souls, angry souls, oh lord Bring love to their souls, to their souls, to their souls So many frightened souls, frightened souls, oh lord
Oh lord, oh lord Bring knowledge to this land Knowledge to this land So much confusion in the land Oh lord, oh lord Bring knowledge to this land Knowledge to this land So much confusion in the land
Come heal this broken landlord, broken landlord So much trouble in the land, trouble, so much trouble
Come heal this broken land Lord, broken land So much trouble in the land Oh Lord, oh Lord, oh Lord Oh Lord, Lord, Lord, Lord Come heal this broken land Lord, broken land So much trouble in the land Oh Lord, oh Lord Heal this broken land Broken land
broken land. That song is on the radio, by the way. You guys can all hear that. It's on the radio, it's streaming, Bandcamp, all the places.
Prayer for the people.
world of tall land snare. If I falter.
to my kingdom come. Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh
Oh no!
Jacob Means on mandolin. Max Ridley on bass. Hector Faluguzman on drums. Grayson Hillen on guitar. I gotta give a big shout out to Grayson because we just got back I guess last week from this festival we did in
Wisconsin, thank you. And I'd never played duo, like duo shows with two guitars before. And so we worked out a bunch of these songs with, just arranged with two acoustic guitars and two voices and it was so much fun and he held it down so well, so.
Yeah. We've just been playing together this summer. We met at church, actually. So, big shout out to Grayson. This next one is the next single I've got coming up. This is called, May a Love Like This Find Me. And it comes out, I believe, in October.
And I wrote this with a couple of wonderful musicians from the great bluegrass group Sister Sadie. And we wrote it, I brought in this theme, this chorus of talking about different scenarios or things that I see in the world that make me seek a love.
Um, that I want to find. Um, and not necessarily romantic love, but, uh, this song talks about the love between friends and the love between a parent and a child. And, um, so I hope you enjoy this. It's called, May a Love Like This Find Me. One, two, three.
A woman walks her husband to the door. Puts on his socks and shoes and leads him where to go. And though he can't recall her name, he knows he's safe. She's there every day. Little girl runs onto the field.
Red on her pants and in her eyes, tears. And Maggie covers her and tells her it's OK. She knows she's safe. She's there every day. May a love like this find me.
May a love like this find me. A love like this find me. Oh, may a love like this find me. May a love like this find me. A love like this find me.
A little boy runs to his mother's arms. His mind is not the same, and making friends ain't easy. He always tries. She understands. He knows he's safe, cause she's there every day.
May a love like this find me. May a love like this find me. A love like this find me. Oh, may a love like this find me. May a love like this find me. A love like this find me.
He heard something in her voice. He pours a glass of wine and meets her at the door. He wonders how she knows like he exists to meet her needs. He knows she's safe because he's there every day. May a love like this find me. May a love like this find me.
A love like this find me. Oh, may a love like this find me. May a love like this find me. A love like this find me. Someone who loves the things you hate about you. Someone who sees you at your worst and loves you still.
Someone who holds you to your life with undying good will. May love like this find me. May a love like this find me. A love like this find me. Oh, may love like this find me. May a love like this find me. A love like this find me.
Grab your coat and get your hat. Leave your worries on the doorstep. Just direct your feet to the sunny side of the street. Can't you hear that bitter pack? And that happy tune is yours there. Life can be so sweet on the sunny side of the street.
I used to walk in the shade with those blues on parade. Oh, but I'm not afraid. This rover crossed over. If I never had a chance, I'd be rich as Rockefeller. Gold dust at my feet on the sunny side of the street.
Ž Ž Ž
Bum bum bum bum bum bum bum bum bum.
Max Ridley.
Grab your coat and get your hat. Leave your worries on the doorstep. Just direct your feet to the sunny side of the street. Can't you hear that pitter-patter? And that happy tune is your step.
Life can be so sweet on the sunny side of the street. I used to walk in the shade with those blues on parade. Oh, but I'm not afraid. This rover is crossover. If I never, never had a cent, I'd be rich as rock.
♪ On the sunny side of the street ♪ ♪ On the sunny side of the street ♪ ♪ On the sunny side of the street ♪ Thank you, thank you so much. We just got one more song for you.
Thank you for being such a wonderful audience. Thank you again to Terry for having us out. It's just been such a pleasure. One more time for Jacob Means. Max Ridley. Hector Falu Guzman. And Grayson Hillen.
I gotta shout out Hector now. This is only our second show together. It's our second show together. And the first show he did, it was a trio thing. And I said, I think I want percussion on one song. And then he ended up playing like half the set, I think. Right? Like, he sounds so good. I have to have him on everything. So you guys remember
There was this terrible storm that blew through in January. I was in New Orleans for Folk Alliance. And I almost got stuck. A bunch of people almost got stuck. And it was that storm that shut the whole Northeast down for three days. And then it went through all of the South. And Nashville froze over. And a bunch of people lost their power for a couple weeks. And it was a big mess. And I was thinking about Leahy.
potentially getting snowed in in your new home and like all of all of this stuff and just thinking about all the people who are trying to get home to their loved ones. And so I wrote this song, Caught in a Storm. And so it's about being caught in a storm with wanting to be caught in a storm with the people that you love, both literally and metaphorically. Thank you. That's the word I was looking for.
I have stickers, and they're free. And I would love for you to take a sticker and scan the QR code and sign up for my mailing list. You can get all the updates on what I'm doing and my shows and everything that I've got coming up. So please grab a sticker. I think they're over here at this table. Or no, they're back there with Liza. Everybody say hi, Liza. Both ways is great.
This is called Caught in a Storm.
New England is cold this time of year And lately the storms haven't come But this time it seems more likely than not We'll find ourselves caught in one Charles is frozen, the wind minus him Been gone the whole week through Trying to make it back Just so that I can be caught in the storm with you
Caught in a storm with you There's no place I'd rather be Than caught in a storm with you One bitter evening you looked in my eyes And said there's something I should know
I said, I'll be right here, and I'll stay through it all. The wind, the rain, and snow. My love is far greater than any old fear of what the gray skies bring. I'm living by faith, and I'm running straight into the eye of the storm with you.
God in a storm, God in a storm with you. There's no place I'd rather be than God in a storm with you.
I'm living by faith and I'm running straight into the eye of the storm with you. Oh caught in a storm, caught in a storm with you. There's no place I'd rather be than caught in a storm with you.
There's no place I'd rather be than caught in the storm with you. Thanks so much. I'm Farai. One more?
Let's do flowers, let's do flowers. All right, this one is called Where Flowers Grow. And I wrote it when I was in a very dark, or when I was coming out of being in a very dark place. And it's just a song about gratitude, about being grateful for being alive and being on the other side of darkness. It's called Where Flowers Grow.
All the things I asked myself maybe 10 years ago. Can I stand on solid ground? Should I lie where flowers grow? Can I be more in control of the thoughts that bring me down?
Will the angel on my shoulder ever take the demons down?
Will I be so discontent with each curve in the road? Will I have some gratefulness and learn to stand on that alone? Can I be more in control of the thoughts that bring me down?
Everything I know I'll ask myself when I'm older and gray. Will I wish I'd said goodbye? Will I be so glad I stayed? I think that I'll be glad I stayed when I lie where flowers lay.
Can I be more in control of the thoughts that bring me down? Will the angel on my shoulder ever take the demons down? Thank you. Thank you. I'm Parai.
So, wow. So what we're trying to do here is we're trying to establish a tradition now of having at least one big voice every time we come out and do the Jazz Festival. So last year we had Donna McElroy, and y'all know what that was. And this year it's Farahi Malik, and it was just huge. So thank you so much. Thank you so much.
Once again, the Farai Malik Quintet, Farai Malik on vocals and acoustic guitar, Grayson Hillen on electric guitar, Jacob Means on vocals and meandering, Max Ridley back here on vocals in the upright bass, and Hector Falu Guzman on the traps back here. Marvelous, just marvelous.
No worries, so we're gonna need to take a little pause for the cars to switch over groups. So I'll be back with you in a little while, but in the meantime, please go inside and check out the offerings of the Danish Pastry House. They have some real deliciousness there. They've got savory, they've got sweet, so please go check them out. Check out the t-shirts upstairs on the deck.
You know, that mint green and that bright orange, right, will set your wardrobe off for the next month. So you need to have one of those in your collection. So we're free, but we're not cheap. So make sure that you make a donation to the cause. See Shayla, she's got the red box, you know, drop a little coin or a little folding money, preferably folding money.
in there, and we're happy to have you here. We hope you're enjoying yourselves, and we will be back very shortly with Mina Cho and her group, so get ready for something additionally special. Thank you.
And the sunlight hurts my eyes. And it's breaking my heart you're leaving. Maybe I'm grieving. But if you want to leave, take good care. Hope you have a lot of nice things to wear. But then a lot of nice things turn bad.
It's hard to get by just upon a smile. Oh, baby, baby, it's a wild world. I'll always remember you like a child, girl. You know I've seen a lot of what the world can do.
there but just remember there's a lot of bad and beware beware oh baby baby it's a wild world it's hard to get by just upon the smile oh baby baby it's a wild world
Baby, I love you. But if you want to leave, take good care. Hope you make a lot of nice friends out there. Just remember there's a lot of bad and beware. Well, oh, baby, baby, it's a wild world. It's hard to get by just upon the smile.
Oh, baby, baby, it's a wild world. And it's hard to get by just upon a smile. Oh, baby, baby, it's a wild world. And I'll always remember you like a child, girl.
I just can't remember
just got to see me
My back turned towards the sun. Who knows when the cold wind blows, it'll turn your head around. Well, there's hours of time on the telephone line to talk about things to come. Sweet dreams and flying machines in pieces on the ground.
People say this town don't look good in snow. You don't care, I know. Banshera Highway in the sunshine, where the days are longer, the nights are stronger.
through your hair. And the days surround your daylight there. Seasons crying no despair. Alligator lizards in the air.
in the sunshine where the days are longer the nights are stronger than
see
you
here.
I'm sorry.
you
Check. I'm just talking. I'm not singing though, but it's okay. I'll be talking too. Hello everyone.
Operator.
You know what I mean? But it's OK.
you
All right, all right. So we are back, live and in living color. So I mentioned when I was introducing Farai and her group that we met at Somerville Community Baptist Church. Stacey Clayton, who's a great singer, who's been in this area for years and years,
She does an annual concert with Pastor David and Mina and folks over at Somerville Community Baptist. And I've been lucky enough, fortunate enough, for them to bring me on board to do poetry and to emcee. And I met Farai, and I also met Mina, who is the director of music at the church. But she's much more than that.
The Minichuk Cho Quartet brings the bold, joyful sound of gugak jazz, where Korea's century-old rhythms, felt melodies, and ritual traditions meet the improvisational fire of modern jazz. So prepare for something very, very different.
led by pianist and composer Dr. Mina Cho. And I actually like to call her double doctor because she actually has two doctorates. One from Brenda?
New England Conservatory, and one from Brandeis. And she's a Boston-based jazz pianist, composer, and really, really a scholar in all areas of musicology and so forth. So you're in for not only an education, but also a treat.
in terms of musical excellence. She's bringing a wonderful group to you. This is the Mina Cho Quartet, and it includes Dr. Cho. It also includes George Lernes on drums. Okay, now here's where I could get messed up really, really bad. Young Chae Jung.
Okay, on what I always refer to as the big sexy, the big bass over there with the hourglass figure. Yes, real nice. And then Matthew, I can do that. Book of the Bible, perhaps I can get that one right. Ryu. Okay, all right. And he is on guitar. All right, so this is going to be a treat. I've been looking forward to it for months. Ladies and gentlemen, the Minacho Quartet.
Hello, everyone. Thank you so much for coming to this opportunity. We are so grateful, and thank you so much, Terry and Jonathan, for your warm invitation. The first tune we are playing is called G Street Dance. I came up with this title, this cool title, and it is based on Korean traditional rhythm called gutgeori jangdan. Geori means street, gut.
It has many meanings. One of the meanings is shamanic ritual, but it can also be good performances or good rhythms. I guess we are doing all of these. It's a good performances, good rhythms. We are prepared to play for you and it's a celebration for all of you, for the community. Thank you so much.
do do
you
do
Thank you so much. The second tune we are going to play is called Unmyeong. Unmyeong is Korean. It can be translated as destiny, fate. Why are you here today in this place?
It seems like everything is coincidence, but I believe it's based on our so many decisions that we have made in our lives and precious meetings and the moments that we've had in our life. So thank you so much for being here. I think it's our fate to be present in this moment. So this is Unmyeong Destiny. Hope you enjoy. Thank you.
Ž Ž
do do
do
do do do
you
Ž Ž
Thank you so much. That was George Lerness on many percussion instruments. We have cajon, we have darbuka, he has a frame drum, and he has tambourine-like instruments called raq. Raq, Arabic instruments, a lot of Arabic tambourine, yes. We have Matthew Liu on the guitar. Again, we have Young Chae Jung on the bass.
Are you enjoying Minacho Quartet music so far? Okay, thank you. The next tune we are playing is called Dalmaji. Guess what? We have a lot of Korean titles today. Dalmaji means greeting the moon. In Korea, there's, in many Asian countries, as a matter of fact, there's a tradition of celebrating the night of the full moon, wishing for a happy year or rich harvest in the old days.
So this is my hope and our wish through this music you have a rich, I guess, emotions and good feelings and positive energy today. So this is Dalmaji, Greeting the Moon, but I titled it Night of the Full Moon. Night of the Full Moon. Thank you.
you
I happen to know one of the famous Korean folk songs called Arirang. Arirang, you never heard of it? Okay, Arirang is one of the famous Korean folk songs, but the tricky thing is there are so many Arirangs according to each region, little regions in Korea.
And this particular Arirang is from eastern, northern eastern part of Korea. And it's called the Miryang Arirang. Traditionally the song goes like the refrain part goes like this. Do you want to hear it? So that, yeah, you become familiar with the melody.
Would you repeat after me if you don't mind?
Okay, so this tune is based on this melody, beautiful melody.
♪
you
do do
Thank you so much. It's about the time we finish. You wanna hear one more tune before we go? Yes, would you like, yeah? Time okay? Yeah, okay. Go to me, go to me, yes. Thank you so much for being here again. Let me introduce amazing friends of mine one last time. Matthew Liu on the guitar.
George Lennes on percussion, hybrid drum set, Young Chae Jung on the bass, and I was Mina Cho on the piano. Thank you so much, Terry, Reverend Terry Carter, and Jonathan, and everyone, thank you so much for your warm invitation again.
you
do
All right. One more time for the Minichow Quartet. So I'm probably going to spend the rest of the night puzzling over how George got all of that sound out of that box back there. So it's pretty amazing stuff. In any case, Minichow on piano and Korean traditional instrument.
George Lennox on the drums, Young Taejong on bass, and Matthew Ryu on guitar. Really, really different, beautiful music, obviously. And really a change of pace from what we heard earlier in the day and what we heard yesterday. And tomorrow, you'll want to be on hand if you can be.
We have the Niko Guerrero Trio. We have another group from, as we have every year, from the Berklee Institute of Jazz and Gender Justice, which is directed by Terry Lynn Carrington. And then, not to pat ourselves on the back, but myself, Jonathan Fagan back there,
Greg Toro and Gordon Engelgauld, the Ally Project, will be entertaining as the last set of the day. So we hope that you can come back and enjoy the show. It's been a blast. A couple things I want to remind you of. My friends, Tracy and Deakin from the Danish Pastry House.
They still have snacks available if you want some, you know, go inside and go inside and eat, yes, and enjoy. And we've had just a wonderful, wonderful sponsorship from Method Community Media, my goodness. Jim's here representing them. We have audience, Avey Fagan is here.
Audience Sound Company, the Berklee Institute of Jazz for Gender Justice, Winchester Music School, Morningside Music Studio, the Arts Alive Foundation, and the Medford Arts Council. It's been
a real special time for us, especially in terms of bringing on new Patreon subscribers who have helped to advance our efforts throughout the year, and then the sponsors that have jumped on board kind of towards the end of this thing.
Tomorrow, come on out. We'll be here. We'll be enjoying the day with you. The tents will still be up. The chairs will be here. The music will be good. And the food will still be available from Danish Pastry House. Starts at 2 o'clock. First band, Nico Guerrero Trio, Berklee Institute of Gender and Jazz.
Jazz and Gender Justice at three o'clock, and then the Ally Project at four o'clock. And then you can go out for dinner after that, see?
You'll have had your fill of music and go out and get something nice to eat. And you'll have made a day of it, right? And then if you want to start with church, I'm not mad at you, OK? Go get your worship on at the church, at the temple, wherever you serve. Go on and do that. In any case, thank you, Mina. We appreciate you. Appreciate you, fellas.
Appreciate our audience. OK, so I said it before. I'll say it one more time, right? We're free, but we ain't cheap. So if you want to make a donation, you can see my man Eli. He's got the red box back there. And he'll be happy to take your folding money.
Jonathan, did I forget anything? Okay, all right. Show up tomorrow, okay? And bring cash to donate, okay? And eat, drink, and be merry, all right? For tomorrow we live happy, all right? Have a good evening, everybody. Thank you for joining us here at the Medford Jazz Festival.